Yunyong Ko

Contact Information Room 4219, Siebel Center 201 N Goodwin Ave Urbana, IL 61801, USA

Research Interests My research interest lies in large-scale data mining and machine learning on various types of data (e.g., graph, text, image) for real-world applications to social networks analysis, recommender systems, and information retrieval.

Education

Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

Sep. 2013 - Aug. 2021

Phone: 217-200-0120

Email: yyko@illinois.edu

Homepage: https://yy-ko.github.io

- Ph.D. in Computer Science
- Thesis: "Effective Approaches to Distributed Deep Learning: Methods, Analyses, and Evaluation"
- · Advisor: Prof. Sang-Wook Kim

Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

• B.S. in Computer Science

Mar. 2009 – Aug. 2013

Work Experiences

University of Illionois at Urbana-Champaign, IL, USA

May. 2022 – Present

- Postdoctoral Researcher, Department of Computer Science
- Topic: Large-Scale Machine Learning on Real-World Hypergraphs
- · Advisor: Prof. Hanghang Tong

Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

Sep. 2021 – April. 2022

- Postdoctoral Researcher, Department of Computer Science
- Topic: Optimization Technique for Large-Batch DNN Training
- · Advisor: Prof. Sang-Wook Kim

The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA, USA

Oct. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Visiting Researcher, College of Information Sciences and Technology (IST)
- Topic: Data Parallelism Approach for Distributed Deep Learning
- · Advisor: Prof. Dongwon Lee

Publications

Refereed Conference and Journal Papers (* indicates equal contributions)

[12] KHAN: Knowledge-Aware Hierarchical Attention Networks for Accurate Political Stance Prediction
Yunyong Ko, Seongeun Ryu, Soeun Han, Youngseung Jeon, Jaehoon Kim, Sohyun Park, Kyungsik Han,
Hanghang Tong and Sang-Wook Kim

WWW 2023 (The ACM Web Conference)

Full Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 19.2\%$)

[11] RealGraph^{GPU}: A High-Performance GPU-Based Graph Engine Toward Large-Scale Real-World Network Analysis

Myung-Hwan Jang, Yunyong Ko, Dongkyu Jeong, Jeong-Min Park, and Sang-Wook Kim **ACM CIKM 2022** (*The ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management*) Short Paper (Acceptance Rate ≈ 28.3%)

[10] Not All Layers Are Equal: A Layer-Wise Adaptive Approach Toward Large-Scale DNN Training Yunyong Ko, Dongwon Lee, and Sang-Wook Kim

WWW 2022 (The ACM Web Conference)

Full Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 17.7\%$)

[9] D-FEND: A Diffusion-Based Fake News Detection Framework for News Articles Related to COVID-19 So-Eun Han, Yunyong Ko, Yusim Kim, Heejin Park, Seongsu Oh, and Sang-Wook Kim **ACM SAC 2022** (The ACM Symposium on Applied Computing) Full Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 24\%$) [8] SHAT: A Novel Asynchronous Training Algorithm That Provides Fast Model Convergence in Distributed Deep Learning Yunyong Ko, and Sang-Wook Kim Applied Sciences 2022 (SCIE, IF:2.679) [7] MASCOT: A Quantization Framework for Efficient Matrix Factorization in Recommender Systems {Yunyong Ko*, Jae-Seo Yu*}, Hong-Kyun Bae, Yongjun Park, Dongwon Lee, and Sang-Wook Kim **IEEE ICDM 2021** (The IEEE International Conference on Data Mining) Full Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 9.9\%$) Selected as One of the Best-ranked Papers of ICDM 2021 for Fast-track Journal Invitation [6] ALADDIN: Asymmetric Centralized Training for Distributed Deep Learning Yunyong Ko, Kibong Choi, Hyunseung Jei, Dongwon Lee, and Sang-Wook Kim **ACM CIKM 2021** (The ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management) Full Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 21.7\%$) Selected as One of the Spotlight Presentations of CIKM 2021 [5] An In-depth Analysis of Distributed Training of Deep Neural Networks Yunyong Ko, Kibong Choi, Jiwon Seo, and Sang-Wook Kim **IEEE IPDPS 2021** (The IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium) Full Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 24.5\%$) [4] Influence Maximization for Effective Advertisement in Social Networks: Problem, Solution, and Evaluation Suk-Jin Hong, Yunyong Ko, Moon-Jeung Joe, and Sang-Wook Kim ACM SAC 2019 (The ACM Symposium on Applied Computing) Full Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 24.2\%$) [3] Efficient and Effective Influence Maximization in Social Networks: A Hybrid-Approach {Yunyong Ko*, Kyung-Jae Cho*}, and Sang-Wook Kim **Information Sciences 2018** (SCIE, IF:6.795) [2] Influence Maximization in Social Networks: A Target-Oriented Estimation Yunyong Ko, Dong-Kyu Chae, and Sang-Wook Kim **Journal of Information Science 2018** (SCIE, IF:3.282) [1] Accurate Path-Based Influence Maximization in Social Networks Yunyong Ko, Dong-Kyu Chae, and Sang-Wook Kim **WWW 2016** (*The ACM Web Conference*) Short Paper (Acceptance Rate $\approx 21\%$) Selected as One of the Best-Ranked Papers of IEEE ICDM 2021 • IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Selected as One of the **Spotlight Presentations of ACM CIKM** 2021 · ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management

2021

Received the Outstanding Ph.D. Dissertation Award

· Research Institute of Industrial Science, Hanyang University

Awards

& Honors

	Received the Best Paper Award • Korea Information Processing Society	2021
	Received the ACM SIGAPP Student Travel Award • ACM Symposium on Applied Computing	2019
	Awarded the Naver Ph.D. Fellowship • Naver Corporation	2017
	Received the Best Presentation Award • Korea Computer Congress	2017
Professional Services	Track Co-Chair • ACM Symposium on Applied Computing (ACM SAC)	2023
	 Conference Reviewer ACM Web Conference (WWW) ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (ACM KDD) IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM) AAAI International Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) ACM Symposium on Applied Computing (ACM SAC) 	2023 2021, 2022 2022 2021 2022, 2023
Invited Talks	Not All Layers Are Equal: A Layer Wise Approach Towards Large Scale DNN Trainin	A CT

Invited Talks

Not All Layers Are Equal: A Layer-Wise Approach Towards Large-Scale DNN Training

• Invited Talk @ METU-HANYANG Joint Workshop, Dec. 2022

Basic Concept of Distributed Deep Learning with PyTorch Tutorials

· Invited Talk @ Medical AI Korea, Oct. 2021

Patents

International Patents

 $\bullet \ \ \textbf{Asymmetric Centralized training for Distributed Deep Learning} \ (PCT \ application)$

Application number: PCT/KR2021/015014, Date: Oct. 2021

Domestic Patents

· A Layer-Wise Adaptive Approach toward Large-Scale DNN Training

Application number: 10-2022-0075800, Date: June. 2022

· Multi-State Diffusion Model using Interest, Intimacy, and Share Tendency

Registration number: 10-2332348, Date: Dec. 2020

· Accurate Ad-Effect Estimation Method based on Relevance between User and Item

Registration number: 10-2144122, Date: Aug. 2020

• Influence Maximization in Social Networks: A Hybrid Approach to Solving Performance Issues in

Micro and Macro Levels

Registration number: 10-1810864, Date: Dec. 2017